<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<codeBook xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI/Version1-2-2.xsd" xmlns="http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI" version="1.2.2" ID="ARG_1980_PHC_v01_A_IPUMS">
  <docDscr>
    <citation>
      <titlStmt>
        <titl>National Population and Housing Census, 1980</titl>
        <IDNo>DDI_ARG_1980_PHC_v01_A_IPUMS</IDNo>
      </titlStmt>
      <prodStmt>
        <producer abbr="MPC" affiliation="University of Minnesota" role="Documentation">Minnesota Population Center</producer>
        <prodDate date="2010-12-09">2010-12-09</prodDate>
        <fundAg abbr="OECD/DCD-PARIS21" role="Project funder">Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development, Development Co-operation Directorate</fundAg>
        <grantNo>JADE#:60525;MEHLB(2010)12</grantNo>
      </prodStmt>
      <verStmt>
        <version><![CDATA[Version 1.0. Documentation of census data and harmonized variables as found in IPUMS-International. The International Household Survey Network (IHSN) contracted IPUMS International for generating DDI and Dublin Core-compliant metadata related to population and housing census datasets from developing countries. The objective was to provide countries with detailed metadata in a format compatible with the DDI standard used by most of these countries, with a view to guarantee the preservation of the data and metadata, and the publishing of metadata.

The intellectual rights (including copyright) for the data and metadata in IPUMS are retained by the countries under a Memorandum of Understanding with the contributing countries. IPUMS-International has distribution rights to the metadata and data. The XML documents generated by this process are viewed as a distribution of the metadata.]]></version>
      </verStmt>
    </citation>
  </docDscr>
  <stdyDscr>
    <citation>
      <titlStmt>
        <titl>National Population and Housing Census, 1980</titl>
        <IDNo>ARG_1980_PHC_v01_A_IPUMS</IDNo>
      </titlStmt>
      <rspStmt>
        <AuthEnty>Argentine National institute of Statistics and Censuses</AuthEnty>
        <AuthEnty affiliation="University of Minnesota">Minnesota Population Center</AuthEnty>
      </rspStmt>
      <prodStmt>
        <copyright>(c) Copyright 1980, Argentine National institute of Statistics and Censuses and Minnesota Population Center</copyright>
      </prodStmt>
      <distStmt>
        <contact>Argentine National institute of Statistics and Censuses</contact>
      </distStmt>
      <serStmt>
        <serName>Population and Housing Census [hh/popcen]</serName>
        <serInfo/>
      </serStmt>
      <verStmt>
        <version date="2010-12-09">Version 1.0. This version contains selected variables from the original census micro data plus harmonized variables from the IPUMS International data base.</version>
      </verStmt>
    </citation>
    <stdyInfo>
      <subject>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Technical Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Group Quarters Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Geography Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Economic Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Utilities Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Dwelling Characteristics Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Constructed Household Variables -- HOUSEHOLD</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Technical Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Constructed Family Interrelationship Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Demographic Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Fertility and Mortality Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Education Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Work Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Migration Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Work: Occupation Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="IPUMS">Work: Industry Variables -- PERSON</topcClas>
      </subject>
      <abstract><![CDATA[IPUMS-International is an effort to inventory, preserve, harmonize, and disseminate census microdata from around the world. The project has collected the world's largest archive of publicly available census samples. The data are coded and documented consistently across countries and over time to facillitate comparative research. IPUMS-International makes these data available to qualified researchers free of charge through a web dissemination system.

The IPUMS project is a collaboration of the Minnesota Population Center, National Statistical Offices, and international data archives. Major funding is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation and the Demographic and Behavioral Sciences Branch of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Additional support is provided by the University of Minnesota Office of the Vice President for Research, the Minnesota Population Center, and Sun Microsystems.]]></abstract>
      <sumDscr>
        <timePrd date="1980-10-22" event="start"/>
        <timePrd date="1980-10-22" event="end"/>
        <collDate date="1980-10-22" event="start">The interviews take place on the expected census day.  In some areas the enumeration took place the following day because of access problems due to heavy rains.</collDate>
        <collDate date="1980-10-23" event="end"/>
        <nation abbr="ARG">Argentina</nation>
        <geogCover>National coverage</geogCover>
        <geogUnit><![CDATA[Department]]></geogUnit>
        <anlyUnit>Dwelling, quarter dwelling, census household, and population</anlyUnit>
        <universe>All the population in the national territory at the moment the census is carried out.</universe>
        <dataKind>Census/enumeration data [cen]</dataKind>
      </sumDscr>
      <notes><![CDATA[UNITS IDENTIFIED:
- Dwellings: Yes
- Vacant units: Not available in microdata sample
- Households: Yes
- Individuals: Yes
- Group quarters: Yes

UNIT DESCRIPTIONS:
- Dwellings: Any lodging fixed or movable that has been built or adapted to be inhabited by people. A private dwelling is occupied by private households. A dwelling inhabited by six or more lodgers is considered to be a group quarters household.
- Households: A person or a set of people, relatives or not, which occupy the same dwelling.
- Group quarters: A dwelling occupied by a group of people that share the dwelling under a non-family arrangement due to the following reasons: work, military, health, religion, discipline.]]></notes>
    </stdyInfo>
    <method>
      <dataColl>
        <sampProc><![CDATA[MICRODATA SOURCE: Argentine National Institute of Statistics and Censuses (INDEC)

SAMPLE DESIGN: In locations where the sample fraction is 10 percent, 100 percent of households are chosen. In locations where the sample fraction is 20 percent, every 2nd household is chosen with a random start. For the remaining locations were there is not a sample, every 10th household is chosen. In group quarters, the sample was not applied in the enumeration. They are chosen as a systematic sample of every 10th person with a random start. The sample was elaborated by INDEC.

SAMPLE UNIT: Household

SAMPLE FRACTION: 10%

SAMPLE UNIVERSE: 100% of the population and households enumerated. The 1980 census used a sample for the application of the long questionnaire form. The fraction of the sample varies according to the size of location.

SAMPLE SIZE (person records): 2,667,714]]></sampProc>
        <deviat/>
        <collMode>Face-to-face [f2f]</collMode>
        <resInstru>Short form questionnaire: (1) Dwelling questionnaire (2) Population questionnaire (both questionnaires made up a single booklet). Long form questionnaire: (1) Dwelling questionnaire (2) Population questionnaire (both questionnaires make up a single booklet).</resInstru>
        <sources></sources>
        <collSitu>De facto, CENSUS DAY: October 22, 1980, FIELD WORK PERIOD: The interviews take place on the expected census day.  In some areas the enumeration took place the following day because of access problems due to heavy rains.</collSitu>
        <actMin>Direct enumeration via house-to-house visits and personal interviews performed by teachers called upon to perform census activities as public obligation.</actMin>
        <weight><![CDATA[Computed by census agency and should be used for most types of analysis.]]></weight>
      </dataColl>
      <anlyInfo>
        <respRate>COVERAGE: 98.99%</respRate>
      </anlyInfo>
    </method>
    <dataAccs>
      <useStmt>
        <confDec required="yes"><![CDATA[IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved.

To gain access to the data, a researcher must agree to the following:

(1) Implement security measures to prevent unauthorized access to census microdata. Under IPUMS-International agreements with collaborating agencies, redistribution of the data to third parties is prohibited.

(2) Use the microdata for the exclusive purposes of scholarly research and education. Researchers must explicitly agree to not use microdata acquired for any commercial or income-generating venture.

(3) Maintain the confidentiality of persons, households, and other entities. Any attempt to ascertain the identity of persons or households from the microdata is prohibited. Alleging that a person or household has been identified is also prohibited.

(4) Report all publications based on these data to IPUMS-International, which will in turn pass the information on to the relevant national statistical agencies.

Once a project is approved, a password is issued and data may be acquired through the Internet. Penalties for violating the license include: revocation of the license, recall of all microdata acquired, filing of a motion of censure to the appropriate professional organizations, and civil prosecution under the relevant national or international statutes.

These safeguards mirror the principles from the Joint ECE/Eurostat Work Session on Statistical Data Confidentiality. Employees of the Minnesota Population Center who work with the census microdata to produce the harmonized database also sign agreements to respect the confidentiality of the data.

IPUMS-International works with each country's statistical office to minimize the risk of disclosure of respondent information. The details of the confidentiality protections vary across countries, but in all cases, names and detailed geographic information are suppressed and top-codes are imposed on variables such as income that might identify specific persons. In addition, IPUMS-International uses a variety of technical procedures to enhance confidentiality protection. These include the following:

(1) Swapping an undisclosed fraction of records from one administrative district to another to make positive identification of individuals impossible.

(2) Randomizing the placement of households within districts to disguise the order in which individuals were enumerated or the data processed.

(3) Aggregating codes of sensitive characteristics (e.g., grouping together very small ethnic categories)

(4) Top- and bottom-coding continuous variables to prevent identification of extreme cases.

The safety record for public-use census microdata is apparently perfect. In almost four decades of use, there has not been a single verified breach of statistical confidentiality. The measures implemented by the IPUMS-International are designed to extend this record.]]></confDec>
        <contact affiliation="Minnesota Population Center" URI="http://international.ipums.org">IPUMS International</contact>
        <citReq><![CDATA[Minnesota Population Center. Integrated Public Use Microdata Series, International: Version 6.0 [Machine-readable database]. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota, 2010.

Researchers should also acknowledge the statistical agency that originally produced the data:
Argentina, Argentine National institute of Statistics and Censuses, National Population and Housing Census, 1980

The licensing agreement for use of IPUMS-International data requires that users supply IPUMS-International with the title and full citation for any publications, research reports, or educational materials making use of the data or documentation.

Copies of such materials are also gratefully received at ipums@pop.umn.edu.

Printed matter should be sent to:
IPUMS-International
Minnesota Population Center
University of Minnesota
50 Willey Hall
225 19th Avenue South
Minneapolis, MN 55455
]]></citReq>
        <conditions><![CDATA[An adapted version of the dataset, harmonized for international comparability, is available from IPUMS-International (https://international.ipums.org/international/) under the following conditions:

IPUMS-International distributes integrated microdata of individuals and households only by agreement of collaborating national statistical offices and under the strictest of confidence. Before data may be distributed to an individual researcher, an electronic license agreement must be signed and approved.  To gain access to the data, a researcher must agree to the following:

(1) Implement security measures to prevent unauthorized access to census microdata. Under IPUMS-International agreements with collaborating agencies, redistribution of the data to third parties is prohibited.

(2) Use the microdata for the exclusive purposes of scholarly research and education. Researchers must explicitly agree to not use microdata acquired for any commercial or income-generating venture.

(3) Maintain the confidentiality of persons, households, and other entities. Any attempt to ascertain the identity of persons or households from the microdata is prohibited. Alleging that a person or household has been identified is also prohibited.

(4) Report all publications based on these data to IPUMS-International, which will in turn pass the information on to the relevant national statistical agencies.

Once a project is approved, a password is issued and data may be acquired through the Internet. Penalties for violating the license include: revocation of the license, recall of all microdata acquired, filing of a motion of censure to the appropriate professional organizations, and civil prosecution under the relevant national or international statutes.

These safeguards mirror the principles from the Joint ECE/Eurostat Work Session on Statistical Data Confidentiality. Employees of the Minnesota Population Center who work with the census microdata to produce the harmonized database also sign agreements to respect the confidentiality of the data.
]]></conditions>
        <disclaimer>The user of the data acknowledges that the original collector of the data, the authorized distributor of the data, and the relevant funding agency bear no responsibility for use of the data or for interpretations or inferences based upon such uses.</disclaimer>
      </useStmt>
    </dataAccs>
    <othrStdyMat>
      <relMat type="Document, Questionnaire [doc/qst]">
        <citation>
          <titlStmt>
	    <titl>Censo Nacional de Poblaci?n y Vivienda 1980-Decreto N 2781/79 (con.)</titl>
	  </titlStmt>
	  <rspStmt>
	    <AuthEnty>Instituto Nacional de Estad?stica y Censos</AuthEnty>  
	  </rspStmt>
	  <prodStmt>
	    <producer>Instituto Nacional de Estad?stica y Censos, Centro LatinoAmericano de Demograf?a (CELADE) </producer>
	    <prodDate date="1980-10-22">October 22, 1980</prodDate>
	  </prodStmt>
	  <holdings URI="documents/enum_form_ar1980_long.pdf"/>
        </citation>
      </relMat>
    </othrStdyMat>
  </stdyDscr>
  <fileDscr ID="P">
    <fileTxt>
      <fileName>ARG1980-P-H.dat</fileName>
      <fileCont>Person records</fileCont>
      <fileStrc type="rectangular">
      </fileStrc>
      <dimensns>
        <caseQnty>2667714</caseQnty>
      </dimensns>
      <fileType>ascii</fileType>
      <filePlac>Minnesota Population Center</filePlac>
      <verStmt>
        <version>Version 1.0, IPUMS sample</version>
      </verStmt>
    </fileTxt>
  </fileDscr>
  <dataDscr>
    <var ID="AR80A_SEX" files="P" name="AR80A401" intrvl="discrete" dcml="0">
      <location StartPos="149" width="1" EndPos="149"/>
      <labl>Sex</labl>
      <qstn><qstnLit><![CDATA[
2. Is the person a man or a woman?

[] Man
[] Woman

]]></qstnLit><ivuInstr><![CDATA[
2. Male or female? 
You will fill out the corresponding cell.
]]></ivuInstr></qstn>
      <universe clusion="I">All persons</universe>
      <txt><![CDATA[This variable indicates the person's gender.]]></txt>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>1</catValu>
        <labl>Male</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">1331444</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>2</catValu>
        <labl>Female</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">1336270</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <concept vocab="IPUMS">Demographic Variables -- PERSON</concept>
      <varFormat schema="other" type="numeric"/>
    </var>
    <var ID="AR80A_AGE" files="P" name="AR80A402" intrvl="discrete" dcml="0">
      <location StartPos="150" width="2" EndPos="151"/>
      <labl>Age</labl>
      <qstn><qstnLit><![CDATA[
3. What is his or her age? _ _

Mark the age in completed years at the date of the census for those younger than one year old mark 00. For those younger than 10 years old, mark 01, 02, 03, etc. For those older than 99 years old, mark 99.

]]></qstnLit><ivuInstr><![CDATA[
3. What is your age?
You will mark the information of the enumerated person in completed years on the date of the census.

You will fill out the corresponding cells. In all cases, you should use both columns of cells. Writing in the first, the tens, and in the second, the single units. Consult the indications given on the back of the questionnaire.
]]></ivuInstr></qstn>
      <universe clusion="I">All persons</universe>
      <txt><![CDATA[This variable indicates the person's age in years.]]></txt>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>00</catValu>
        <labl>0</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">72622</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>01</catValu>
        <labl>1</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">67317</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>02</catValu>
        <labl>2</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">69867</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>03</catValu>
        <labl>3</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">70175</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>04</catValu>
        <labl>4</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">66812</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>05</catValu>
        <labl>5</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">65382</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>06</catValu>
        <labl>6</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">60329</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>07</catValu>
        <labl>7</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">58343</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>08</catValu>
        <labl>8</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">59000</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>09</catValu>
        <labl>9</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">56501</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>10</catValu>
        <labl>10</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">56699</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>11</catValu>
        <labl>11</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">52624</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>12</catValu>
        <labl>12</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">52917</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>13</catValu>
        <labl>13</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">50324</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>14</catValu>
        <labl>14</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">49830</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>15</catValu>
        <labl>15</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">50555</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>16</catValu>
        <labl>16</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">48455</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>17</catValu>
        <labl>17</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">46501</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>18</catValu>
        <labl>18</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">46012</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>19</catValu>
        <labl>19</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">39519</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>20</catValu>
        <labl>20</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">42371</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>21</catValu>
        <labl>21</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">40166</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>22</catValu>
        <labl>22</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">41996</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>23</catValu>
        <labl>23</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">43587</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>24</catValu>
        <labl>24</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">41624</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>25</catValu>
        <labl>25</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">41673</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>26</catValu>
        <labl>26</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">39572</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>27</catValu>
        <labl>27</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">40475</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>28</catValu>
        <labl>28</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">40353</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>29</catValu>
        <labl>29</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">38502</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>30</catValu>
        <labl>30</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">42349</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>31</catValu>
        <labl>31</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">34713</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>32</catValu>
        <labl>32</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">36989</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>33</catValu>
        <labl>33</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">35837</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>34</catValu>
        <labl>34</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">33010</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>35</catValu>
        <labl>35</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">35004</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>36</catValu>
        <labl>36</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">32572</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>37</catValu>
        <labl>37</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">30494</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>38</catValu>
        <labl>38</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">31775</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>39</catValu>
        <labl>39</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">29727</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>40</catValu>
        <labl>40</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">33792</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>41</catValu>
        <labl>41</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">25399</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>42</catValu>
        <labl>42</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">29135</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>43</catValu>
        <labl>43</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">27395</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>44</catValu>
        <labl>44</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">25358</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>45</catValu>
        <labl>45</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">28122</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>46</catValu>
        <labl>46</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">25073</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>47</catValu>
        <labl>47</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">25147</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>48</catValu>
        <labl>48</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">27231</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>49</catValu>
        <labl>49</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">26806</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>50</catValu>
        <labl>50</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">29263</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>51</catValu>
        <labl>51</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">22655</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>52</catValu>
        <labl>52</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">25814</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>53</catValu>
        <labl>53</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">24094</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>54</catValu>
        <labl>54</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">23374</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>55</catValu>
        <labl>55</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">23215</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>56</catValu>
        <labl>56</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">22136</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>57</catValu>
        <labl>57</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">20498</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>58</catValu>
        <labl>58</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">20980</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>59</catValu>
        <labl>59</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">19450</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>60</catValu>
        <labl>60</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">21519</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>61</catValu>
        <labl>61</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">14911</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>62</catValu>
        <labl>62</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">16329</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>63</catValu>
        <labl>63</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">15730</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>64</catValu>
        <labl>64</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">15472</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>65</catValu>
        <labl>65</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">17066</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>66</catValu>
        <labl>66</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">14628</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>67</catValu>
        <labl>67</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">14065</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>68</catValu>
        <labl>68</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">13669</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>69</catValu>
        <labl>69</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">12331</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>70</catValu>
        <labl>70</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">13614</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>71</catValu>
        <labl>71</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">9709</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>72</catValu>
        <labl>72</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">10288</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>73</catValu>
        <labl>73</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">9288</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>74</catValu>
        <labl>74</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">8581</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>75</catValu>
        <labl>75</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">9015</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>76</catValu>
        <labl>76</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">7705</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>77</catValu>
        <labl>77</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">6274</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>78</catValu>
        <labl>78</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">6217</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>79</catValu>
        <labl>79</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">5232</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>80</catValu>
        <labl>80</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">5889</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>81</catValu>
        <labl>81</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">3219</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>82</catValu>
        <labl>82</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">3232</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>83</catValu>
        <labl>83</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">2759</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>84</catValu>
        <labl>84</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">2597</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>85</catValu>
        <labl>85</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">2277</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>86</catValu>
        <labl>86</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">1752</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>87</catValu>
        <labl>87</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">1445</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>88</catValu>
        <labl>88</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">1170</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>89</catValu>
        <labl>89</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">961</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>90</catValu>
        <labl>90</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">881</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>91</catValu>
        <labl>91</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">460</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>92</catValu>
        <labl>92</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">440</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>93</catValu>
        <labl>93</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">285</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>94</catValu>
        <labl>94</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">263</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>95</catValu>
        <labl>95</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">205</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>96</catValu>
        <labl>96</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">160</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>97</catValu>
        <labl>97</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">97</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>98</catValu>
        <labl>98</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">95</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>99</catValu>
        <labl>99+</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">374</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <concept vocab="IPUMS">Demographic Variables -- PERSON</concept>
      <varFormat schema="other" type="numeric"/>
    </var>
    <var ID="AR80A_CITIZ" files="P" name="AR80A407" intrvl="discrete" dcml="0">
      <location StartPos="160" width="1" EndPos="160"/>
      <labl>Citizenship</labl>
      <qstn><qstnLit><![CDATA[
6. [Immigration status]

Only for persons who have usual residence in Argentina and were born in another country.
[Questions 6A and 6B asked only of persons born outside Argentina and who currently reside in Argentina.]



B. Are you a naturalized citizen of Argentina?


[] Yes
[] No
[] Unanswered

]]></qstnLit><ivuInstr><![CDATA[
6. Only for persons born abroad who usually reside in Argentina.
a) You will complete the year.

[The instructions refer to a graphic of the census form.]

b) You will fill out the corresponding cell.
]]></ivuInstr></qstn>
      <universe clusion="I">Foreign-born persons who reside in Argentina </universe>
      <txt><![CDATA[This variable indicates whether or not the person is a naturalized citizen of Argentina.]]></txt>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>1</catValu>
        <labl>Yes</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">33248</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>2</catValu>
        <labl>No</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">116198</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>8</catValu>
        <labl>Unknown</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">11417</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>9</catValu>
        <labl>NIU (not in universe)</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">2506851</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <concept vocab="IPUMS">Nativity and Birthplace Variables -- PERSON</concept>
      <varFormat schema="other" type="numeric"/>
    </var>
    <var ID="AR80A_EDCOMP" files="P" name="AR80A411" intrvl="discrete" dcml="0">
      <location StartPos="164" width="1" EndPos="164"/>
      <labl>Completed highest level of education</labl>
      <qstn><qstnLit><![CDATA[
9. [Educational attainment]

If the person answered "Attend" or "Attended but does not attend":
[Questions 9A-9D asked of those who had ever attended an educational institution.]



A. What level does the person attend or is the highest that he or she attended?


[] Preschool
[] Elementary
[] Pre university
[] Commercial
[] Teacher's training
[] Technical or industrial
[] Other middle level
[] Higher education not university
[] University
[] Unanswered



B. Did he complete this level?


[] Yes
[] No
[] Unanswered

]]></qstnLit><ivuInstr><![CDATA[
9. If they answered "attends" or "does not attend but attended."
You will ask:

a) for the highest level advanced at the moment of the census.

b) if they passed or not, this level.

c) about the last year or grade passed.
Take into account, that in the primary level there was a change in names with 1st grade superior becoming 2nd grade, 2nd becoming 3rd, . . . . . 6th becoming 7th fill in the cell that corresponds to the current name.

[To the right of the text are two forms.]

[p. 11]

d) about the major or university career that is or was studied, writing the name of the major or career.

Vague positions or titles like: Graduate, Doctor, Engineer, etc, should not be put down.

[The instructions refer to a graphic of the census form.]

Possible educational levels

Preschool

Primary: Common primary schools, boarding schools, schools for adults, schools for children with special needs, centers of adult literacy, schools in hospitals, schools in prisons, schools annexed to the Armed Forces.

[The instructions refer to a graphic of the census form.]

Secondary: National secondary schools, high schools, specialized preparatory schools.

Commercial: Business schools.

Teacher training: Teacher training schools, regional teaching schools.

Technical or industrial: Industrial schools, advanced night school, regional and coeducational industrial schools, professional schools for women, factory schools, schools of worker training, schools of professional training for women, institutes of electrical technology, agricultural technical school, schools of medical aids. In all the cases they should be courses that require having completed the primary cycle.

Other middle educational: Institutes of middle specialized education: Military School, Navel School, Police and Firefighter school, Penitentiary Schools, Schools of Sub-officials of the Armed Forces, rural and domestic cultural missions [misiones de cultura rural y doméstica], schools of artistic education, Nautical School.

Higher not university: Professors of: History, Physical Education, Pedagogy, Languages, etc. Teachers specialized in: kindergarten, children with special needs, deaf mutes, the blind, etc. Specialized not teaching: courses for graduates of industrial schools, journalists, librarians and museum curators. Higher Military Schools: Military Secondary School, Naval School, Higher School of War, etc. University: Departments of Medicine, Engineering, Architecture, Law, etc.

]]></ivuInstr></qstn>
      <universe clusion="I">Persons age 5+ who ever attended educational institution </universe>
      <txt><![CDATA[This variable indicates whether the person completed the highest educational level.]]></txt>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>1</catValu>
        <labl>Yes</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">719169</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>2</catValu>
        <labl>No</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">1415193</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <catgry>
        <catValu>9</catValu>
        <labl>NIU (not in universe)</labl>
        <catStat type="freq">533352</catStat>
      </catgry>
      <concept vocab="IPUMS">Education Variables -- PERSON</concept>
      <varFormat schema="other" type="numeric"/>
    </var>
  </dataDscr>
</codeBook>